In this video, we'll look at
这节课 我们将学习
three different techniques for doing hierarchical clustering,
除单连接聚类法以外的
other than single link clustering.
三种不同的层次聚类法
As a matter of fact,
事实上
if you try to do single link clustering in Scikit-learn,
如果你要在 Scikit-learn 框架中使用单连接聚类法
you will not be able to because it's not there.
你是做不到的 因为压根没有
The three hierarchical clustering techniques we'll be looking at in this video are all
我们这节课要学习的三种层次聚类法都是
part of the agglomerative clustering component of Scikit-learn,
Scikit-learn 框架中凝聚聚类成分的一部分
which does not actually include single link clustering,
所谓凝聚聚类法并不包括单连接聚类法
but it does include complete link clustering.
但包括全连接聚类
Agglomerative clustering is this part of
凝聚聚类法是层次聚类法的一部分
hierarchical clustering that starts from the bottom up,
同样是自下而上
assuming that each point is a cluster and then building out the other clusters.
先假设每个点是一个类 然后由此建立其他的类
So this is to separate it from a different part of hierarchical or clustering,
所以 要区分开这种聚类法与其他的聚类法或者层次聚类法
where it assumes everything is one cluster and
那些聚类法先假定所有事物都是一个类
then it breaks it down into smaller clusters.
然后将这个大类分成若干小类
Complete link clustering works very similarly to single link clustering.
全连接聚类法和单连接聚类法的运作模式非常相似
And so it would start out the same way,
它们的开始方式都是一样的
assuming each point is its own cluster,
假定每个点是一个类
and then it would compute all the distances between
然后计算任意两个类之间的距离
all the clusters and then merge the nearest two clusters.
再把距离最近的两个类合并成一个类
And so the closest two clusters in the beginning would be 4 and 5,
所以 首先 距离最近的两个类是 4 号点和 5 号点
and so we put them in a cluster.
我们把它们合并成一个类
We note that on the side.
标记在右侧
And then 1 and 2, and then 6 and 8,
然后合并 1 号点和 2 号点 6 号点和 8 号点
just like single link.
就像单连接聚类法一样
There's a little bit of a difference here,
这儿有一点不同
where the distance between 7 and
7 号点和橙色类之间的距离
the orange cluster is not the distance between 7 and the closest point, 6.
并不是 7 号点和离它最近的 6 号点之间的距离
Complete link actually looks at the farthest two points in the two clusters,
全连接聚类法关注的是两个类中两点之间的最远距离
and that is the distance between two clusters.
将它定义为两类之间的距离
And so 7 and 8 is actually the distance between this cluster,
因此 这两个类之间的距离就是 7号点和 8 号点之间的距离
containing only one point,
其中一个类只包含一个点 7 号点
7, and this orange cluster.
另外一个类就是这个橙色类
And so that would turn out to be the minimum distance between clusters,
这就是两个类之间的最小距离
and so it would merge the two clusters,
所以将它们合并成一个类
just the same as single link but for a different reason here.
跟单连接聚类法一样 但聚类的原理有所区别
This step is the only difference between single link and
在这个示例的数据集中 这一步
complete link in this example dataset.
是区分单连接聚类法和全连接聚类法的唯一区别
And then we continue to build out our tree until we have our entire tree.
然后我们继续建构系统树 直到最后形成一个完整的系统树
And then we have the choice of,
然后 我们就要选择
how many clusters do we want? Do we want two?
我们想要几个类？两个？
We break the tree here,
那么我们在这个地方切断树
and we have this as one cluster,
这是一个类
and this as another cluster.
这是另一个类
So, the distance measure in complete link is
所以 全连接聚类法中的距离衡量方法
the two farthest points between two clusters.
是两类中最远的两点之间的距离
So if we have a step,
假设我们走一步
we arrive at a step,
这一步是
where we have these three clusters.
我们有三个类
The distances between pink one and the purple one is this,
那么粉色类和紫色类之间的距离
the farthest two points.
就是最远的这两点之间的距离
The distance between green and purple is this,
绿色类和紫色类之间的距离就是这两点间的距离
and the distance between green and pink is this.
绿色类和粉色类之间的距离就是这两点之间的距离
And so now, we have calculated the distances between the clusters that we have,
现在我们已经计算出了所有类之间的距离
we choose the minimal distance between two clusters,
接着来选择一下两类间的最小距离
and then we group those two clusters together.
然后将这两个类合并成一个类
A distance measure like this in complete link produces compact clusters,
全连接聚类法中 这样的距离衡量方法使得产生的类比较紧凑
which are generally thought of as better than the clusters produced by single link.
比单连接聚类法产生的类更紧凑 更好
But then again, the best distance measure
但同样 最佳距离衡量方法
really depends on your dataset and what you're trying to achieve.
取决于数据集和目标效果
One challenge with complete link,
全连接聚类法的挑战是
just like we mentioned with single link,
和我们在单连接聚类法中讲到的一样
is that it's only looking at this one point.
只关注一个点
Once it's determined what the two farthest points are,
一旦确定最远两点后
it stops considering the other points.
就不再考虑其他的点了
And so in a case like this,
所以在这个例子中
where these points might have been maybe part of another cluster here,
这些点可能是其他类的一部分
complete link, in fact,
但是
disregards them and only looks at the farthest points.
全连接聚类法就忽视了他们 只考虑最远的两点
And so it might be good to think about other ways to calculate the distance measure.
因此 可能要寻找其他的方式来计算距离
This includes our next example, average link.
这些方式就包括 组平均聚类法
This is also in Scikit-learn, and basically,
它也是 Scikit-learn 框架的一部分 通常
it looks at the distance between every point and every other point in the other cluster.
它计算的是任意两类中任意两点之间的距离
And then the average of all these distances is the distance between the two clusters.
然后取平均值 即为两类之间的距离
Finally, we have Ward's method.
最后 还有离差平方和法
This is the default method in Scikit-learn for hierarchical clustering,
这是 Scikit-learn 框架中一种预设的层次聚类法
and it's a method that tries to minimize variance when merging two clusters.
这种方法的目的是把合并类时的变量最小化
The way Ward's method calculates the distance between clusters,
离差平方和法计算两类间的距离的方法是
let's say clusters A and B here,
例如计算图中类 A 与类 B 之间的距离
is that it would try to find a central point, and that's simple.
找一个中心点 这一步很简单
That's just averaging all these points that would give you a central point.
取所有点之间的平均位置 所得即为中心点
And then we can calculate the distance between every point and the center point.
然后就算所有点与中心点之间的距离
And then we raise that to the power of two,
分别计算其平方
and then add them all up like this.
然后把结果相加
But then we have to subtract the variance already existing in the clusters.
但我们要减去类中的变量
We do that by estimating the central point in the cluster,
方法是找每个类中的中心点
so this is the central point in cluster A,
这是类 A 的中心点
and then we subtract A_1 square and subtract A_2 square,
然后减去 A1 的平方 减去 A2 的平方
which are the distances between the first point in
A1 指的是第一个点到类 A 中心点之间的距离
the center and the second point in the center.
A2 指的是第二个点到类 A 中心点之间的距离
We do the same thing with Cluster B as well,
类 B 也是同样的计算方式
and then that would be the distance between these two clusters.
最后结果就是这两个类之间的距离
We do the same with these two clusters,
计算这两个类之间的距离也是用同样的方法
and then these two clusters,
然后计算这两个类之间的距离
and then whichever one is least,
最后结果中哪个数值最小
we merge those two clusters.
就把相关的两个类合并成一个类
And that is Ward's method.
这就是离差平方和法
In the next concept,
下节课中
we'll be looking at implementation.
我们将介绍具体的使用方法